# Ibney Alom

## **UI** Developer

A self-motivated IT professional with knowledge and proficiency in Angular 4+, Typescript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and mobile responsive web development as well as strong skills and ability in writing clean and efficient code with 1.5+ years of experience in Front end development.



ibney1992@gmail.com

+91 7002436738

Bangalore, India

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **UI Developer**

# Molecular Connections Pvt Ltd

11/2018 – Present Bangalore

Molecular Connections Private Limited is the pioneering In silico discovery services company with proven expertise in drug-discovery, biocuration, informatics and information technology. Molecular Connections is a leading supplier of manually curated databases and informatics solutions to major pharmaceuticals, high throughput data analysts and systems biology companies across the globe.

#### Responsibilities

- Developing user interfaces using Angular as per design and information architecture.
- Build reusable code and libraries for future use.
- Optimize application for maximum speed and scalability
- Make design and technical decisions for projects.
- Delivering a complete front end application.
- Cooperating with the back-end developer in the process of building the API.
- Ensuring high performance on mobile and desktop.
- Guide Junior developers and Interns

# **Graduate Engineer Trainee**Funfirst Global Skillers Pvt Ltd

08/2015 – 11/2016

Guwahati

Funfirst Global Skillers Pvt Ltd provides industry-need responsive vocational skills and products to increase employability and productivity of the youth, quality and awareness of teachers and improvement in essential life skills.

#### Responsibilities

- Develop training plans and deliver training on Mobile, Refrigerator, AC, Washing Machine Repairing
- Provide flexible learning and assessments which meet the learning needs of a range of students
- Participate in curriculum development, material development, testing, evaluation and feedback tools.
- Responsible for growing the business in North-East, India

# **EDUCATION**

B.Tech

Dibrugarh University

08/2011 - 07/2015

# **SKILLS**

Angular 4+ Typescript Javascript HTML

CSS

SCSS

D3.js

Bootstrap

# **PROJECTS**

#### **IET Inspec Analytics**

- IET's Inspec Analytics named 'Best New Product/Service' in The Charleston Advisor's Eighteenth Annual Readers' Choice Awards -November 13, 2019
- Inspec Analytics is based on the IET's Inspec database and was developed to support researchers, strategic managers and libraries in assessing the value and impact of research and make strategic decisions about the direction of their projects, departments and collaborations

#### Journal Recommendation Service

The FSTA Journal Recommendation Service (JRS) is an online tool
designed for researchers and authors working in the sciences of
food and health. The JRS helps users to find relevant journals they
can trust; for example, when deciding where to submit their papers,
or when assessing if a journal is a suitable information source for
their research.

### Microbiology Criteria

 Microbiology Criteria provides guidance to all those involved in producing, using and interpreting microbiological criteria in the food and catering industries

#### American Psychological Association Admin UI

 It is an admin UI for the client where admin can manage mainly three modules like Mail, Conferences, Template by adding editing and deactivating. Also admin can update data by uploading excel file.

#### Phibase 5.0

 The mission of PHI-base is to provide expertly curated molecular and biological information on genes proven to affect the outcome of pathogen-host interactions. Information is also given on the target sites of some anti-infective chemistries.

### **Novartis POC**

 Novartis was released for POC. Basically it shows relation between terms using graphical visualization

#### MC-Spider

 It's a tool where we can configure and manage crawling. One of the main feature of this tool is we can preview the xapths and heading of a particular URL.